<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="newspaper.xsl" ?><noticias>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>'The movement is larger than ... a single person's story'</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>08:24</hora>
        <autor>By Ashley Fantz, Ray Sanchez and Faith Karimi, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>us</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)The president of the NAACP Spokane, Washington, chapter Rachel Dolezal has resigned, according to a letter from her which was posted Monday on the NAACP Spokane Facebook page.Dolezal did not address allegations that have landed her and her family in the national spotlight over the past several days. Her parents, who are white, allege that she has been lying and presenting herself as black when she is not.The story ignited debate over race and identity and blew up on social media.In her letter to the NAACP's executive committee and its member, she wrote, "I have waited in deference while others expressed their feelings, beliefs, confusions and even conclusions -- absent the full story. I am consistently committed to empowering marginalized voices and believe that many individuals have been heard in the last hours and days that would not otherwise have had a platform to weigh in on this important discussion."Additionally, I have always deferred to the state and national NAACP leadership and offer my sincere gratitude for their unwavering support of my leadership through this unexpected firestorm."She said that though "many issues face us now" such as "police brutality, biased curriculum in schools, economic disenfranchisement, health inequities, and a lack of pro-justice political representation ... the dialogue has unexpectedly shifted internationally to my personal identity in the context of defining race and ethnicity.""While challenging the construct of race is at the core of evolving human consciousness, we can NOT afford to lose sight of the five Game Changers (Criminal Justice &amp; Public Safety, Health &amp; Healthcare, Education, Economic Sustainability, and Voting Rights &amp; Political Representation) that affect millions, often with a life or death outcome. The movement is larger than a moment in time or a single person's story, and I hope that everyone offers their robust support of the Journey for Justice campaign that the NAACP launches today!" the letter reads.While she is "delighted that so many organizations and individuals have supported and collaborated with the Spokane NAACP under my leadership to grow this branch," she wrote that she "can see that a separation of family and organizational outcomes is in the best interest of the NAACP."She said that she has "complete allegiance to the cause of racial and social justice and the NAACP" and is passing her role to the chapter's Vice President Naima Quarles-Burnley."Please know I will never stop fighting for human rights and will do everything in my power to help and assist, whether it means stepping up or stepping down, because this is not about me. It's about justice. This is not me quitting; this is a continuum," she wrote.Shortly after the post appeared, some on Twitter weighed in.Earlier a member of the chapter appeared on CNN to say that others were upset about a Monday meeting that the NAACP has postponed. It was expected that Dolezal would explain herself then."People want resolve. They want some kind of closure" to the controversy that has triggered national headlines about Dolezal, debates over race and identity, and put the NAACP in the spotlight, chapter member Kitara Johnson said on CNN on Monday morning.Johnson said that members want clear direction from the national office of the NAACP about how to handle Dolezal's future with the organization, and in the meantime, Johnson has started a petition to make Dolezal take a leave of absence.On Sunday, the Spokane chapter of the NAACP issued a statement: "Due to the need to continue discussion with regional and national NAACP leaders, tomorrow's meeting is postponed and will be rescheduled for a later date."Dolezal hasn't made a public statement."All the information hasn't come out completely," Johnson said. "We want to ask her, in a nice way and be respectful of the work she's done in the community, to take a leave of absence to take care of her personal issues (so) the work of social justice and equity can move forward."Dolezal's estranged parents have spoken to the media about her misrepresentation."We are her birth parents," her father, Lawrence Dolezal, said Friday. "We do not understand why she feels it's necessary to misrepresent her ethnicity."CNN contacted Dolezal last week, and she declined an interview. She said she stands by her record of service and hoped to address the accusations at Monday's meeting.Dolezal has said she received threatening hate mail in the past, but the Spokane Police Department told CNN's Poppy Harlow that it dropped its investigation of the letters because of a lack of leads. The investigation was dropped before the controversy about her race became public.Johnson said her concern isn't that Dolezal may be white, but rather that she was perhaps untruthful about that."We have never called (whether she should lead) into question in terms of race," Johnson said. "Martin Luther King said we don't want to be judged by the color of our skin, (but) ... on the content of our character."More of Dolezal's relatives have joined the chorus of criticism.Her adopted brother, Ezra Dolezal, said she took him aside three years ago and asked him "not to blow her cover" about her alternate identity."She said she was starting a new life ... and this one person over there was actually going to be her black father," he said.Dolezal has identified herself as at least partly African-American, but her Montana birth certificate states she was born to two parents who say they are Caucasian. The parents shared that document and old photos with CNN.She began identifying herself more with the African-American community in 2007, according to her parents.The regional NAACP leader has said her race is not a factor.What Dolezal has done is more important to the NAACP than what race she is, regional President Gerald Hankerson said. He called the NAACP a civil rights organization first that includes "leaders from all different ethnicities," adding that it "doesn't do a genealogy search on what a person's ethnicity is when they" take a top position."We represent all civil rights issues, regardless of a person's ethnicity. And the quality of the work that she has done to elevate the issues of civil rights in that region is what we applaud," he said.A peaceful protest against Dolezal is planned outside the NAACP office in Spokane on Monday, CNN affiliate KXLY reported.CNN's Stephanie Elam, Paul Vercammen, Greg Botelho, Tony Marco and Ralph Ellis contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612092018-rachel-dolezal-split-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/15/rachel-dolezal-naacp-leader-resigns-elam-sot-lv.cnn-ap</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/us/washington-rachel-dolezal-naacp/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Brother: Rachel Dolezal's appearance is 'blackface'</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/13</data>
        <hora>02:33</hora>
        <autor>By Ray Sanchez and Ben Brumfield, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>us</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)Ezra Dolezal says he didn't know how to respond the day his adopted sister took him aside and asked him "not to blow her cover" about having a black father.On that day three years ago, he said, Rachel Dolezal, 37, told him she was starting life anew in Spokane, Washington, where she's now head of the local chapter of the NAACP and chairwoman of a police oversight committee.Ezra Dolezal, 22, came to visit her from Montana, where their parents live. His adopted sister was on her way to becoming one of the most prominent faces in Spokane's black community."She told me not to blow her cover about the fact that she had this secret life or alternate identity," Ezra Dolezal said Saturday. "She told me not to tell anybody about Montana or her family over there. She said she was starting a new life ... and this one person over there was actually going to be her black father."Dolezal's race has come under question after her estranged mother claimed she is white but is "being dishonest and deceptive with her identity."Dolezal has identified herself as at least partly African-American but her Montana birth certificate states she was born to two parents who say they are Caucasian. The parents shared that document and old photos with CNN."I kind of saw it coming," Ezra Dolezal said of the controversy. "Instead of sticking to a simple story, she's been trying to make this really complex and it finally got too big for her to handle."CNN contacted Dolezal on Saturday. She declined an on-camera interview, saying she stands by her record of service and referring CNN to a statement from the NAACP on Friday. Dolezal told CNN she would likely speak Monday night at the NAACP meeting in SpokaneThe Spokane Spokesman-Review, meanwhile, reported that she has framed the controversy surrounding her racial identity in the context of litigation over guardianship of her adopted brother."We are her birth parents," Lawrence Dolezal told CNN on Friday. "We do not understand why she feels it's necessary to misrepresent her ethnicity."Rachel Dolezal grew up in what her parents called a diverse family, with friends from various ethnicities and four adopted siblings who are black. She was "always interested in ethnicity and diversity" growing up, her mother Ruthanne Dolezal said.Dolezal attended college in Mississippi, then went on to Howard University on scholarship -- not having identified herself as black then on her application because there was no such option, though people there may have assumed as much "because her portfolio of art was all African-American portraiture," her mother said.It wasn't until around 2007, her parents said, that Dolezal began identifying herself more with the African-American community, according to her mother.Her parents say Rachel Dolezal "has chosen to distance herself from the family."According to court documents obtained by CNN, Rachel Dolezal's adopted brother, Izaiah -- who is black -- sought emancipation from Ruthanne and Lawrence Dolezal in 2010. The adopted brother, now 21, said the Dolezals used "physical forms of punishment" and had sent his brother and sister away to group homes because they didn't cooperate with the couple's religion and rules.The adopted brother wanted to live with Rachel Dolezal "in a multiracial household where black culture is celebrated and I have a connection to the black community," the court papers said. The papers did not specify Rachel Dolezal's race.Ezra Dolezal said the accusations of physical punishment were false. They divided the family. He said he never confronted his adopted sister when she asked him not to blow her cover because he didn't want to make the situation worse.His adopted sister was always interested in African-American culture but it wasn't until about 2011 that he started to notice physical changes."There was the gradual darkening of the skin and the hair," he said. "She started molding herself into who she is today."He said Dolezal's transformation was tantamount to living in "blackface.""It's kind of a slap in the face to African-Americans because she doesn't know what it's like to be black," said Ezra Dolezal, whose biological mother was white and father half-black. "She's only been African-American when it benefited her. She hasn't been through all the struggles. She's only been African-American the last few years."Izaiah's petition for emancipation was dropped. In a separate legal action in 2010, the court appointed Rachel Dolezal to be the adopted brother's guardian with the consent of Ruthanne and Lawrence Dolezal.Ezra Dolezal said he admires his adopted sister's appreciation and advocacy for the black community and culture. But he questions her handling of the race issue."I believe that the first most important thing regardless of what a person does is that they have integrity," he said. "Rachel has done really good work fighting against racism and police brutality ... but she went about it the wrong way. She said I was born black. I grew up black and I know what it's like growing up as an African-American in this world. She does not."Dolezal's time at predominantly black Howard University may have been a major turning point in her transformation, her adopted brother said."When she applied they thought she was a black student," he said. "When she came there, they saw she was white and she wasn't treated that well, especially by people that worked there. She probably started developing this kind of dislike for being white and dislike for white people. She used to tell Izaiah ... that all white people are racists. She might have developed some self-hatred."On Friday, the Dolezals told CNN they didn't want to comment on a possible "legal dispute" that their daughter and the NAACP had mentioned.One organization that appears to be standing behind her is the NAACP. The group, historically one of the most prominent in supporting causes important to the African-American community, said that Dolezal is "enduring a legal issue with her family" and that "we respect her privacy in this matter.""One's racial identity is not a qualifying criteria or disqualifying standard for NAACP leadership," the group said. "The NAACP Alaska-Oregon-Washington State Conference stands behind Ms. Dolezal's advocacy record."Dolezal allegedly represented herself as African-American -- along with several other ethnicities, including white and Native American -- in an application for a Spokane police ombudsman commission.And she has presented the public with a different family photograph posted to the local NAACP chapter's Facebook page. When she announced her father was coming to town for a visit, she showed herself standing next to an older African-American man.Dolezal's public racial identity came under scrutiny on Thursday, when a reporter from CNN affiliate KXLY held up that photo and asked her if it showed her dad. She replied that it did.Then came a follow-up question: "Are you African-American?""I don't understand the question of -- I did tell you that, yes, that's my dad. And he was unable to come in January," Dolezal responded."Are your parents -- are they white?" came the next query.Dolezal walked away from the microphone, leaving her purse and keys, and took refuge in a nearby clothing boutique.Dolezal has built a wide-ranging career as an expert on and advocate for the black community.She is not just president of her local NAACP chapter; she is also an academic expert on African-American culture and teaches many related classes at Eastern Washington University.She represents the black community publicly and vocally, including as a spokeswoman on race-influenced police violence. On Tuesday she spoke to Al Jazeera on the topic. And Dolezal has appeared alongside Baltimore City State's Attorney Marilyn Mosby, who has filed charges against police officers in the death of Freddie Gray, a young black man.The mayor of Spokane appointed Dolezal chairwoman of a police oversight committee to keep an eye on fairness in police work.After the allegations of faked racial identity surfaced, Mayor David Condon and City Council President Ben Stuckart said they take "very seriously the concerns raised regarding the chair of the independent citizen police ombudsman commission."The city is checking to see if she has violated any policies.Still, what Dolezal has done is more important than what race she is to the NAACP, regional President Gerald Hankerson said. He called the NAACP a civil rights organization first that includes "leaders from all different ethnicities," adding that it "doesn't do a genealogy search on what a person's ethnicity is when they" take a top position.As to Dolezal specifically, Hankerson said, "We represent all civil rights issues, regardless of a person's ethnicity. And the quality of the work that she has done to elevate the issues of civil rights in that region is what we applaud."CNN's Stephanie Elam, Paul Vercammen, Greg Botelho, Tony Marco and Ralph Ellis contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612092018-rachel-dolezal-split-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/12/naacp-rachel-dolezal-dnt-malveaux-lead.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/13/us/washington-rachel-dolezal-adopted-brother/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Top official sentenced to life for bribery</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/11</data>
        <hora>10:36</hora>
        <autor>By Steven Jiang and Jason Hanna, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)The highest-ranking Chinese Communist Party official ever to face corruption charges has been sentenced to life in prison, according to a statement Thursday from China's Supreme People's Court.Zhou Yongkang, the country's former security chief, received the sentence after being found guilty of taking bribes, China's top court said, citing the Tianjin No. 1 Intermediate People's Court in northeastern China.Zhou, 72, also received seven years for abusing power and four years for deliberately revealing state secrets.Footage from the court in Tianjin, not far from the Chinese capital, Beijing, showed Zhou looking healthy but now with white hair.He said, "I have acknowledged the fact of my committed crimes, and the loss that was caused to the party's mission. Hereby I am pleading guilty and I am regretful of it."As a member of the ruling Communist Party's Politburo Standing Committee -- China's top decision-making body -- Zhou was one of nine men who effectively ruled the country of more than 1.3 billion people. He retired in 2012.At the height of his power, Zhou controlled police forces, spy agencies, court systems and prosecution offices across China -- and wasn't shy in deploying his vast assets to crush dissent and unrest in the name of "preserving social stability."But prosecutors said Zhou took advantage of his posts to seek benefits for others and illegally accepted large amounts of money during his long political career.State media have painted an intricate web of officials, cronies and tycoons -- some with alleged mafia connections -- orbiting around Zhou before the crumbling of his power structure last summer.He was expelled from the Communist Party and arrested in December before being formally charged in April.Zhou and his family members were said to have accumulated enormous wealth in a blatant exchange between money and power.He was also found to have affairs with multiple women and allegedly traded power for sex, the state-run Xinhua news agency reported last year.Analysts have viewed his shocking downfall as a watershed moment in the secretive world of Chinese politics, now ruled by President Xi Jinping.Xi has been spearheading a massive anti-corruption campaign, targeting both "tigers" and "flies" -- high-ranking, and low-level, officials.Who is Zhou Yongkang?CNN's Steven Jiang reported and wrote from Beijing, and CNN's Jason Hanna wrote in Atlanta. CNN's David McKenzie and Kevin Wang contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/141205221939-zhou-yongkang-may-2012-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/11/zhou-yongkang-prison-sentence-china-mckenzie-lok.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/11/asia/china-zhou-yongkang-sentence/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Aung San Suu Kyi arrives in Beijing</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/10</data>
        <hora>10:48</hora>
        <autor>By Tim Hume, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)Myanmar's opposition leader Aung San Suu Kyi has met Chinese President Xi Jinping as she begins a trip that will emphasize the Nobel laureate's apparent transition from human rights defender to pragmatic politician.Suu Kyi met Wednesday with Wang Jiarui, a senior official of the Chinese Communist Party, shortly after touching down in the Chinese capital, according to China's state-run media. Wang is vice chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference and head of the International Department of the Communist Party's Central Committee.Suu Kyi also met with Xi, and she is scheduled to meet with Premier Li Keqiang during her trip, according to her party, the National League for Democracy.Observers say China hopes that the June 10-14 visit, a party-to-party meeting between the National League for Democracy and the Chinese Communist Party, will allow the country to boost its waning influence in its southern neighbor, which has increased engagement with the West during dramatic political reforms in recent years.Meanwhile, Suu Kyi's first visit to China offers an opportunity to burnish her credentials as a stateswoman before national elections later this year, said Aung Zaw, editor-in-chief of The Irrawaddy, a news magazine which specializes in covering politics in Myanmar and Southeast Asia."She's been dubbed a darling of the West, but she's showing she's someone they can work with," he said.Activists are calling on Suu Kyi, who was held under house arrest for nearly 15 years by Myanmar's former military junta, to speak out on human rights issues during her visit to China, which is cracking down on dissent.In particular, Human Rights Watch's Sophie Richardson said in a statement, Suu Kyi should call for the immediate release of her fellow Nobel Peace Prize winner, the writer Liu Xiaobo, who is serving an 11-year sentence for "inciting subversion of state power" by calling for political reform and human rights.But observers say any such move is unlikely."I don't think Beijing is inviting her as an icon of democracy," said Zaw. "I think they're seeing her as a politician who is ready to play."The 69-year-old leader of Myanmar's opposition National League for Democracy has been criticized since her release from house arrest in 2010 for her failure to speak up regarding causes in her country, notably the persecution of the Rohingya Muslim minority, which has created a refugee crisis in the region."The Aung San Suu Kyi we used to know and the one we know today are very different," said Zaw, adding that she had also disappointed some people when a commission she led had approved a controversial Chinese-operated copper mine over the objections of protesters."She has become a politician," Zaw said. "She's no longer a human rights activist."David Mathieson, a senior researcher on Asia for Human Rights Watch, told CNN that China's leaders are confident that Suu Kyi will not embarrass them."Beijing is probably... calculating that Suu Kyi's refusal to speak out on many human rights issues in her own country means she is unlikely to speak out about China's denial of democracy and appalling human rights record," Mathieson said.READ MORE: Why is Aung San Suu Kyi silent on the Rohingya issue?Suu Kyi's visit comes at a turbulent time in the relationship between China and Myanmar.Myanmar, also known as Burma, relied on its northern neighbor as a diplomatic ally and investor during the decades when it was an international pariah state ruled by an authoritarian military junta.But since political reforms in 2011, relations between China and Myanmar's quasi-military government have run "hot and cold" due to a number of issues, said Zaw.In March, five people were killed in China's Yunnan province when a shell from fighting between Myanmar government troops and ethnic Kokang rebels strayed across the border.And China, the largest investor in Myanmar, has been unhappy when major infrastructure projects it has backed, such as the Myitsone dam, have been suspended due to protests."China's leaders can no longer trust Burma's military-backed civilian government to guarantee its many interests in the country," said Mathieson.By building bridges with Suu Kyi, China was underlining its interest in Myanmar, said Zaw."Everyone is coming to play the game over there and I think China is telling them they're a stakeholder," he said.While Suu Kyi cannot run for president -- a clause in Myanmar's military-drafted constitution bars her, as someone who has been married to a foreigner -- her party will likely be more powerful in the new government, said Mathieson."This is China hedging its bets by expanding their relationship with her," he said.The move could also be read as a snub to Myanmar's quasi-military government in light of recent tensions. "The invitation will no doubt upset the Burmese government," said Zaw.A spokesperson for China's Ministry of Foreign Affairs said at a briefing Tuesday that the visit was intended to "further enhance mutual understanding between the two parties, and move forward the China-Myanmar friendly and cooperative relations."Meanwhile, China's state-run Global Times was upbeat about the visit, saying in an editorial it believed Suu Kyi would "become a good friend of China's."CNN's Shen Lu contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150610183450-aung-san-suu-kyi-beijing-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>Sem vídeos disponíveis.</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/10/asia/myanmar-china-suu-kyi-visit/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Ship disaster: 'I wish it was a nightmare'</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/08</data>
        <hora>05:24</hora>
        <autor>By Saeed Ahmed, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)Their hopes have long faded, their prayers gone unanswered. Still, they wait by the banks of the Yangtze River, lighting candles and calling out the names of their loved ones.A week ago Monday, the Eastern Star -- a passenger ship on a pleasure cruise along a stretch of the Yangtze that winds through central China's Hubei province -- went down during a storm. Four hundred and fifty six people -- mostly senior citizens -- were on board.Only 14 survived.By Monday, search crews had recovered 434 bodies. Eight remain missing.It's the deadliest boat disaster in China in almost 70 years."I wish this was a nightmare," Guan Yuan told Xinhua, China's state-run news agency. "But nothing happens when I wake up."Guan's parents were aboard the ship, taking their first long vacation since retiring, she said."My parents rarely traveled to save money for my education," she told the news agency.Bereft of the possibility of a happy reunion, family members had hoped to be able to claim the bodies and take them home. But authorities said that they will be cremated in local funeral homes."It's too bad that people back home won't able to see their deceased family members for the last time," said Hu Jinwei, who lost four members of his family including his mother."I heard bodies were badly damaged. It would be unbearable to see them. I just want my families' (ashes) back home as soon as possible, not suffering anymore."The bodies of Hu's stepfather, aunt and uncle have been identified and he is anxiously waiting to hear if his mother has been identified.So far, forensic teams using DNA to identify the victims have only made 97 matches.The rescue and recovery operation has involved nearly 150 other ships, 59 machines, 3,400 Chinese troops and 1,700 paramilitary personnel, state news agency Xinhua said.Officials have expanded the search area to include more than 600 miles downstream and warned ships to be on the look out for floating bodies.Authorities took the captain and the chief engineer into custody, but have revealed little about what they have said other than that a tornado hit the ship.The Yangtze is the third-longest river in the world, stretching 6,300 kilometers (3,915 miles) from its source in the mountains of Tibet all the way to the East China Sea.The Eastern Star had been making multiple stops on its journey up the river from Nanjing to Chongqing, a city hundreds of kilometers inland. River cruises along the Yangtze are popular among both Chinese and international tourists.It capsized around 9:30 p.m. Monday during a storm over the section of the river that flows through Hubei's Jianli County, authorities said.It's unclear why the Eastern Star was the only ship on the busy waterway so badly affected by the storm.The captain and the chief engineer both said the ship had been hit by a "longjuanfeng," a Chinese word that can be translated as cyclone or tornado, Xinhua reported.The China Meteorological Center said a tornado less than 1 kilometer in diameter and lasting 15 to 20 minutes occurred, China Daily reported.Images of the upended ship evoked memories of the Sewol, the South Korean passenger ferry that sank last year, taking the lives of more than 300 people, most of them high school students. The captain of that ship was convicted of murder in April and sentenced to life in prison.In this case, the majority of the 405 passengers on the cruise were between 50 and 80 years old, according to a list published by state media. The youngest was 3.There were also 46 crew members and five travel agency workers on board, according to state media. All those on board were reported to be Chinese.CNN's Shen Lu and Serena Dong in Beijing journalist Wayne Chang in Hong Kong contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150602070437-02-china-ship-0602-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/05/china-shipwreck-search-and-salvage-watson-pkg.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/08/asia/china-ship-sinking/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>How children are trafficked into Europe</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>18:13</hora>
        <autor>By Nima Elbagir, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
        <corpo>Sicily, Italy (CNN)The 13-year old boy looks off into the distance. He is slight of build with pale, almost yellowy eyes. When you see him you feel as if he has seen far too much already.He is carrying a burden far too heavy for his age -- but despite his ordeal so far, smuggled across continents from Africa to Europe, and now living in a care home, his future could be far worse depending which route he takes next.A CNN investigation spent months retracing the children's journey from Egypt to Italy. Speaking to social workers and authorities, children and parents, there is evidence that many of the children were smuggled into Italy by the same criminal networks, who once they are in country, use them for illegal activities.The Egyptian government agency charged with advising lawmakers on child protection matters told CNN that they believe in some cases the parents are guilty of trafficking, paying for their own vulnerable children to be smuggled so far from home in the hope of securing the family's future.We were interviewing this Egyptian boy and his friends in the picturesque piazza of a small Sicilian town.They came over to Italy together on an Egyptian smuggler ship. He was 12 at the time and crammed in with hundreds of others.He says his parents paid 35,000 Egyptian pounds (about $4,500) for the privilege, never guessing what it would really be like -- tossed around for nine days, surrounded by vomit, and scared, uncertain what would meet them on shore.I asked him what he would say to all the boys back at home, hoping to follow in his footsteps. He said he would warn them not to come but he also said he knew they wouldn't listen."Why would they? I didn't", he says. "Everyone does what their mind tells them. They won't take what we say."I asked if, having suffered so much, he'd make the journey again? "What can I do? Yes. The burden back home is still the same."Italian authorities say he is one of more than 1,000 young Egyptians sheltered in 100 Italian care homes now dotting the Sicilian countryside.The cobbled streets and 17th Century architecture is a very long way from the Nile Delta villages many of the boys have come from.I asked one of his friends if he calls his parents and what he tells them about their lives here, and if he's told them how close to death he came."I tell them nothing, just pleasantries and ask for their prayers. What difference would it make? They need me to make money."These boys tell us their parents went in to debt to raise the fare for their crossing. They saw it as an investment in what they hope will be a better future for the whole family. The children are expected to find work as soon as they can and start sending money home.Here at the care home, that's not possible so thousands of children are disappearing from the Italian social care networks.Italy's Ministry of Labor told us almost 4,000 Egyptian children disappeared from the care system.All the Italian authorities we spoke to who work with these children told us the pressure on the children would be unbearable even for an adult. They fear the consequences to their parents if the smugglers didn't get their money in full, or if the gamble doesn't pay off having sold what little of value they have.The missing children can't work legally. Social workers tell us that too often the children turn to drugs, even prostitution, to get by.Another boy we meet at the home asks me wistfully about Rome, which Italian authorities say is where so many of the disappeared head to.I told him Rome is dangerous for children on their own, especially on the streets. I told him the stories we'd heard from the Egyptian teenagers we'd met in Rome -- the exploitation and the homesickness.The Egyptian children in Rome tell stories of friends selling themselves on street corners -- but they sound suspiciously like they were speaking about themselves.I told him it's better to do it all the legal way and better for him to get an education.He listened politely until I'd finished then told me: "Better to be dead then useless."Dominique Van Heerden, Luca Muzi, Sara Sirgany and Mohamed Kazaz contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612105036-7-migrants-journey-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/elbagir-freedom-project-young-men-gone.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/europe/freedom-project-misery-trail-children/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>U.S. targets terrorist inside Libya, officials say</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/14</data>
        <hora>23:14</hora>
        <autor>By Barbara Starr and Jomana Karadsheh, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>africa</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)U.S. planes carried out a strike inside Libya on Sunday, reportedly killing a key terror figure in North Africa, U.S. and Libyan officials said.The target was Mokhtar Belmokhtar, a veteran Islamist fighter, who is blind in one eye, affiliated with al Qaeda in North Africa, a U.S. official told CNN.The Libyan government said Belmokhtar was killed in the strike, something that U.S. officials have not confirmed.Federal prosecutors in New York had charged Belmokhtar in 2013 with crimes related to a brazen attack on a gas facility in Algeria were 37 hostages died. Three Americans were among the dead.Two F-15 fighter jets dropped multiple 500-pound bombs on a hardened structure in the center of a compound, multiple U.S. defense officials told CNN.U.S. aerial intelligence assets were tracking Belmokhtar's movements at the time of the raid, a Pentagon official with direct knowledge of the operation told CNN, but the outcome of the operation was still being assessed.The initial indication was that Belmokhtar had been killed, the U.S. officials said, but they still lacked an absolute confirmation.The Libyan government went further in a statement Sunday, saying that the U.S. airstrike "led to the killing of Moktar Belmokhtar and a group of Libyans who are members of a terrorist organization in Eastern Libya."The strike happened at 2 a.m. Sunday (8 p.m. ET Saturday).In New York, Belmokhtar was charged on various conspiracy counts including hostage-taking, kidnapping, providing material support to al Qaeda and conspiring to use a weapon of mass destruction.Belmokhtar is the founder of the Signed-in-Blood Battalion, also known as the al-Mulathamun Battalion. The group claimed responsibility for the January 2013 attack in Algeria.In the Algerian siege, heavily armed militants in pickups struck a sprawling state-owned natural gas complex near In Amenas, gathered the Westerners who worked there into a group and tied them up.Belmokhtar had said the attack was in retaliation for Algeria allowing France to use its airspace to battle Islamist militants in Mali.The Algerian military tried to negotiate with the militants during the standoff, but their demands to release militants held prisoner in Algeria were deemed unreasonable, leading to intervention by special forces troops.The gas facility operated in cooperation with foreign energy firms such as Norway's Statoil and Britain's BP -- and as such, employed workers from several Western countries.CNN's Mariano Castillo contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150614190725-mokhtar-belmokhtar-large-169.jpeg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/us-targets-terrorist-in-libya-karadsheh-lklv.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/14/africa/us-airstrike-libya-mokhtar-belmokhtar/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Sudan president flees before arrest</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>11:28</hora>
        <autor>By Don Melvin and Eliott C. McLaughlin, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>africa</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)Sudanese President Omar al-Bashir, a man accused of war crimes and genocide, has left South Africa one step ahead of the law.Al-Bashir left the country Monday just as a South African High Court was considering whether to order his arrest. His departure was confirmed by both the South African and Sudanese governments.Sudan's state news agency, SUNA, reported that Sudanese Foreign Minister Ibrahim Ghandour would hold a press conference at the airport Monday evening "following return of the President of the Republic."Judge Hans Fabricius had ruled Sunday that al-Bashir had to stay in South Africa while a court considered whether he should be arrested. The judge also ordered all ports in the country to prevent the Sudanese leader from leaving.But lawyers arguing in court for al-Bashir's arrest warned, in advance, that the ports of entry and exit were not obeying the judge's order.It is unclear in light of the judge's order what help al-Bashir might have received, and from whom. His plane had been relocated earlier from Tambo International Airport, near Johannesburg, to Waterkloof military base, south of Pretoria.And sometime after that, the alleged war criminal went to the military base and slipped through the net.His departure came as the North Gauteng High Court in Pretoria was considering a request by the International Criminal Court to arrest him on charges of war crimes, crimes against humanity and genocide.The ICC charges against al-Bashir stem from the conflict in the Darfur region in western Sudan, which began in 2003. The government of Sudan has been accused of repression and ethnic cleansing of Darfur's non-Arab population.Al-Bashir had been in South Africa attending a two-day summit of African Union leaders.Fabricius, the judge, said Sunday that he wanted to determine whether it was legally acceptable for Pretoria to allow al-Bashir to visit South Africa without arresting him -- and key in that decision would be determining if the South African Cabinet's decision not to comply with the ICC demand could trump an international treaty, South Africa's Mail &amp; Guardian newspaper reported.The court proceedings began again Monday morning, then went into a one-hour adjournment. South African state lawyer William Mokhari told the court that the best information the government had was that al-Bashir was still in the country.But Isabel Goodman, a lawyer from Southern Africa Litigation Centre, told the court that the country's ports of entry and exit were not being responsive to the court's order."There remains a very real risk that President Bashir will leave," she said, urging the court to hear the matter as quickly as possible.The judge said that, when the court reconvened, he wanted to be informed of which ports of entry were not complying with the emergency order to block ports.After al-Bashir's departure became known, Judge Dunstan Mlambo said it was "of concern to us that an order of this court was not complied with."Mlambo said the government must now file an affidavit on how al-Bashir was allowed to leave, when he left and who signed off on it.Earlier Monday, when al-Bashir's whereabouts were still unclear, the chairman of South Africa's Portfolio Committee on International Relations and Cooperation, Siphosezwe Masango, said he was concerned about the Sudanese President's possible arrest."This is an opportunistic act only meant to pit African leaders against each other in the name of international law," Masango said in a statement. He urged the leaders gathered for the summit to concentrate instead on regional trade, xenophobia, and the development of Africa's infrastructure.He said the ICC appeared to target African leaders and, if the trend continued, his committee might have to recommend that the government re-examine South Africa's membership in the international court.But the U.N.'s high commissioner for human rights, Zeid Ra'ad Al Hussein, warned that member states had to follow ICC rules."It is of deep concern to me and my office when court orders are issued by the ICC in respect of the serving head of state of Sudan, and state parties to the Rome Statute openly flout them," he said Monday at a meeting of the Human Rights Council in Geneva, Switzerland.The Rome Statute was a treaty that established the International Criminal Court."In this regard, we await the ruling of the Pretoria High Court this morning, as it assesses the request submitted by the ICC," he said.Sidiki Kaba, the Senegalese justice minister who serves as president of the assembly of states parties to the Rome Statute, expressed his "deep concern about the negative consequences for the court in case of nonexecution of the warrants by States Parties and, in this regard, urges them to respect their obligations to cooperate with the Court."South Africa, Kaba said in a statement, should "spare no effort" to arrest al-Bashir.South Africa had twice before threatened to arrest al-Bashir -- in 2009 before President Jacob Zuma's inauguration and in 2010 before the World Cup, according to the Southern Africa Litigation Centre. He attended neither event, according to news reports.Arrest warrants from 2009 and 2010 outline the case against al-Bashir and allege that during the Darfur conflict he ordered the military, police and Janjaweed militia to attack three ethnic groups deemed sympathetic to rebel outfits with "the specific intent to destroy in part" those groups.As part of that campaign, the warrants say, the Sudanese president ordered the rape, murder and torture of civilians and the razing of villages.The U.N. has estimated that as many as 300,000 people have been killed in the Darfur conflict since 2003, a tally the Sudanese government says is inflated. Another 7 million are in need of humanitarian assistance, the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees estimates.Putting a face on refugee crisisLast week, the U.N. assistant secretary-general for peacekeeping operations told the Security Council that the ongoing violence in Darfur was having a "devastating" impact on civilians. More than 78,000 civilians have been displaced this year alone, the U.N. reports.CNN's Brent Swails and Tony Wende contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150614114753-omar-al-bashir-au-summit-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/14/pkg-magnay-icc-sudan-south-africa.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/africa/south-africa-summit-icc-omar-al-bashir-arrest/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Paraguay: We're protecting pregnant 10-year-old</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/14</data>
        <hora>02:50</hora>
        <autor>By Kay Guerrero and Catherine E. Shoichet, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>americas</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)Paraguay's foreign ministry says it doesn't need to follow steps recommended by an international human rights committee that weighed in recently on how the country is handling the case of a 10-year-old pregnant girl who was allegedly raped by her stepfather.In a statement released Sunday, the foreign ministry said it rejects a list of demands from the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights about what it should do to protect the life of the girl.Paraguay already "has taken all the appropriate measures to avoid impunity for the wrongful act committed and to ensure the life and safety of this girl and the fetus," the statement said.Last week, the human rights commission, which is part of the Organization of American States, cited recent testimony from U.N. experts saying Paraguay's government had "failed in its responsibility to protect a 10-year old sexual abuse survivor and provide her with critical and timely treatments, including a 'safe and therapeutic' abortion."At issue is Paraguayan law, which bans abortions except in cases where the pregnancy endangers the mother's life. The Paraguayan Ministry of Health has said there's no indication that the health of the girl is at risk.But the human rights commission said that the girl, now 26 weeks pregnant, is facing a serious health situation with a significant possibility of complications. It criticized the Paraguayan government for not releasing enough information about the case and questioned whether the girl and her family were being provided enough information about the situation and the significant medical risks.The mother of the minor has been imprisoned, charged with breaching her care of duty. Last month, police arrested the girl's 42-year old stepfather, accusing him of raping of the child. He denied this accusations.The case has drawn international attention and sparked debate on the largely taboo issue of incest in South America.According to data from UNICEF, in Paraguay, every day two girls from the ages of 10 and 14 give birth to a baby that is the result of sexual abuse.Paraguay's Ministry of Health says that in 2014, over 680 minors from the ages of 10 to 14 reported a pregnancy. Paraguay has a population of 6.7 million.CNN's Rafael Romo and Jason Hanna and journalist Sanie López Garelli contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150501225016-pkg-romo-paraguay-pregnant-10-year-old-00020128-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/02/pkg-romo-paraguay-pregnant-10-year-old.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/14/americas/paraguay-girl-rape-pregnancy/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>South Korea MERS death toll rises to 16; Saudi Arabia reports 5 cases</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>04:37</hora>
        <autor>By K.J. Kwon and Madison Park, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>Seoul, South Korea (CNN)In one sign of a possible return to normalcy, thousands of schools across South Korea re-opened on Monday after closures due to the deadly MERS outbreak.But it came with heightened awareness; children's temperatures were monitored in classrooms and teachers warned students to practice personal hygiene and frequently wash their hands.Not all schools have reopened; 440 remain shut as officials seek to stop the spread of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS).The World Health Organization had recommended re-opening institutions last week because transmission of the virus had not been linked to schools.Nearly four weeks into the South Korean outbreak, cases and deaths continued to mount on Monday.Five new cases of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome have been confirmed in South Korea, bringing the total to 150. Another person also died from the virus, raising the MERS death toll to 16, according to the country's Ministry of Health.The outbreak has sparked international concern, stalled the nation's economy and resulted in over 100,000 canceled tourist visits to the country. Korea's department store sales tumbled 16.5% compared with the same period last year and retail shops also decreased 3.4%, according to the Ministry of Strategy and Finance.The ongoing situation has put Korean authorities under scrutiny for their inability to contain MERS cases and President Park Geun-hye has seen her approval ratings plummet.In a news conference Monday, the Ministry of Health announced that a special task force had been sent to South Korea's second largest city, Busan, after learning that one of the most recently diagnosed MERS patient had visited several hospitals and clinics in the area."We are doing our best to stop the spread of MERS," said the Korean minister of health. "We are analyzing the CCTV with the help of Busan police," referring to tracking down who had been at the hospitals.On Sunday, a 61-year-old man died in a Busan hospital with MERS.South Korean health officials along with a WHO team said this weekend, that the outbreak was slowing, but additional cases were expected.READ: Should you be worried about MERS?Meanwhile, Saudi Arabia has recorded five cases of MERS in the past week, the official state-run Saudi press agency said Sunday, citing a weekly Ministry of Health statement. It included one death of a 73-year-old man who died in the city of Turaba and had a pre-existing condition.The strain of coronavirus that causes MERS was first identified in 2012 in Saudi Arabia, according to the WHO.The man believed to be "patient zero" in the current outbreak in South Korea visited Saudi Arabia in May, along with three other Middle Eastern countries. That 68-year-old patient went from facility-to-facility near or around Seoul before getting properly diagnosed. It triggered the hospital-based transmission of MERS in South Korea.The South Korean outbreak is the largest outside of Saudi Arabia -- over 5,000 people remain in quarantine.In Seoul, Samsung Medical Center -- one of the city's hospitals that has counted many of the nation's MERS cases among its patients and visitors -- announced Sunday that it will suspend all surgical procedures except for emergency surgery "to fully focus on responding to MERS."More than 50 confirmed MERS cases have been traced back to the medical center, according to the center's website.The medical center, located in Seoul's glitzy Gangnam district and considered one of the most prominent hospitals in the capital, issued an apology for its handling of MERS."We sincerely apologize with our heads bent to the people for causing great concern as Samsung Medical Center became the center (of) the spread of MERS," hospital President Song Jae-hoon said.CNN's K.J. Kwon reported from Seoul. CNN's Anas Hamdan reported from Atlanta. Journalists Jung-eun Kim and Han Sol, and CNN's Kay Guerrero and Khushbu Shah contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150607234201-south-korea-mers-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/s-korean-schools-reopen-mers-outbreak-novak-lklv.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/asia/south-korea-mers-outbreak/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Meet septuagenarian who beat virus</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/11</data>
        <hora>22:39</hora>
        <autor>By Kathy Novak, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>Seoul, South Korea (CNN)She's 77 and has chronic asthma. But Kim Bok-soon has also survived MERS, the mysterious virus that's spreading in South Korea and putting thousands in quarantine.Ten people have now died from Middle East Respiratory Syndrome in South Korea; all elderly with pre-existing conditions.It can kill up to a third of people infected, but somehow Kim survived.She had an asthmatic episode and was treated at St. Mary's Hospital in Pyeongtaek between May 4 and May 16. South Korea's "Patient Zero," the man who brought MERS from the Middle East, was at the same hospital at the same time, as the virus started to spread.Kim was sent home with a week's worth of medication. When her condition didn't improve, she went back to St Mary's. Again, doctors sent her home but her symptoms got worse."I felt cold. I was sweating. I coughed all night. I wet my pants because I was coughing so hard," she said. "I thought, 'This is not good.' So I went back to St. Mary's hospital. But they were closed."The hospital had been shut down because dozens of people there had been infected with MERS: patients like Kim, medical staff and visitors. At least 37 cases of MERS have been linked to that initial outbreak.Kim checked into another nearby hospital. By then, South Korean authorities had been shocked into action. The doctors attending to her wore full biohazard suits."They came in covered from head to toe and took blood samples and other things," she said.The tests showed Kim had MERS and she was transferred to Seoul University Hospital.Still Kim, a devout Christian, said she wasn't scared. She continued to pray and rely on God's help as well as medical intervention.The medical staff continued to treat her, so swathed in protective gear that Kim couldn't see their faces properly.She guessed she had beaten MERS the day they came into her room without the white suits."They ran into my room, not even wearing doctors' gowns, and told me, 'You will be going back to general ward!'"I was so happy," she said. "All the doctors and nurses were there in the hallway. They all applauded."She was sent home the next day. "I felt like I could fly."</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150611154436-mers-survivor-kim-bok-soon-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/11/south-korea-mers-patient-novak-pkg.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/11/asia/south-korea-mers-survivor/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>South Korea mulls reopening schools</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/12</data>
        <hora>08:01</hora>
        <autor>By Madison Park and Jung-eun Kim, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>Seoul, South Korea (CNN)The rate of contagion of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome has slowed in South Korea, a health official said Saturday, and may be on its way down. But the outbreak is not completely over.The outbreak has been "large and complex" and "more cases should be anticipated," an official told reporters.Exactly a month ago, a South Korean man walked into a hospital complaining of a cough and fever.The 68-year-old patient, who had just returned from four Middle Eastern countries, went from facility-to-facility before getting properly diagnosed. He would become "patient zero" of South Korea's outbreak of MERS, which has so far reported 138 cases.The outbreak has sparked international concern, shuttered more than 3,000 schools and stalled the country's economy.Fourteen people in South Korea have died after contracting MERS; however, all deaths have been among older adults with underlying medical conditions.Amid weeks of gloomy news, there seems to be gradual signs of easing as officials are mulling the reopening of schools and more people have been released from quarantine after testing negative.Health officials have said this week is crucial in the battle to contain MERS as many of those in quarantine are near the end of their mandatory isolation period.The outbreak in South Korea has had ripples elsewhere around the world.On Thursday, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention issued an advisory, telling American health care providers to watch for MERS symptoms from people coming from South Korea or Middle East countries.Hong Kong and Macau raised travel alerts asking their residents to avoid unnecessary travel to South Korea. Passengers from South Korea to Hong Kong's airport are getting temperature checks.Hong Kong is particularly sensitive to the prospect of an outbreak as it endured hundreds of deaths from the SARS outbreak of 2002-3. But it has not been the only one.China, which also grappled with SARS, has also taken precautions. The Chinese aviation regulator ordered all airlines traveling to Korea to disinfect the plane more frequently, reported Xinhua.Also the organizers of the Shanghai Film Festival, which starts Saturday, emailed Korean participants to say they should cancel their trips due to MERS. The email "was only to provide suggestion," said Yang Xinwei, the festival's spokeswoman.The outbreak has also taken a toll on tourism to South Korea and affected industries such as transportation and restaurants in the country.5 things to know about MERSWhile South Korea has grappled with the outbreak for three weeks, there is some hope of containment.By Friday, 1,249 people had been released from quarantine after they tested negative for MERS. The number of people kept in quarantine has reduced to 3,680, a drop of 125 from the previous day.And schools may be re-opening next week as the Ministry of Health also said there is a "high possibility" of resuming classes. More than 2,700 schools were shut due to MERS on Friday.In a press conference, the Seoul School superintendent announced that all schools should make their own decisions whether to remain closed or not.Earlier this week, the WHO had recommended reopening them since there is no evidence of MERS circulating in schools and only one of over 100 cases has affected a teenager.An expert team assembled by the World Health Organization is scheduled to hold a news conference Saturday, releasing its assessment of the outbreak and the response in South Korea.CNN's Salma Abdelaziz and Kevin Wang contributed to this report from Atlanta. Sol Han contributed to this report from Hong Kong.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150611002252-south-korea-mers-spread-hospitals-large-169.png</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/13/mers-south-korea-outbreak-who-breifing-novak-lok.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/12/asia/south-korea-mers-outbreak/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Hong Kong: 9 accused of conspiring to make explosives</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>11:17</hora>
        <autor>By Tim Hume, Elaine Yu, and Wilfred Chan, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>Hong Kong (CNN)Nine people, some with alleged ties to a radical political organization, have been arrested in Hong Kong, accused of conspiring to manufacture explosives, police in the Chinese territory say.At a news conference Monday, police said they had arrested five men and four women, ranging in age from 21 to 34, whom they described as members of a "local syndicate."Police said their investigations showed that two men in the group were planning to test the powder of an explosive device. They raided a location in the territory's remote Sai Kung district Sunday evening, where they arrested the pair, seized chemicals and detonated explosives.Chemicals recovered during a subsequent house search were tested and found to be precursors of TATP, a highly volatile explosive thought to have been used in the 2005 London bombings and other terror attacks.Officers also found the chemical formula for manufacturing smoke grenades, police said.Police arrested seven others with alleged links to the pair. They also seized air rifles, "V for Vendetta"-style face masks, political stickers and pamphlets, computers containing a sketch of an explosive device, and maps showing locations in Admiralty and Wan Chai -- districts where the city's government is headquartered.Police would not say whether the maps identified targets where the explosives were intended to be used, or whether authorities were working with China's People's Liberation Army, which also has a base in Admiralty."There are maps that show the locations of Admiralty and Wan Chai, and there are possibilities that this group of people might want to do something in this particular location," said Au Chin-chau, chief superintendent of the police Organized Crime and Triad Bureau.Police said some members of the group claimed to be members of a local radical organization. Police would not name the organization.The arrests took place in an abandoned TV studio in Sai Kung. Now derelict and covered in graffiti, the studio is a popular place for photo shoots, teenager parties and paintball-like games with airsoft guns.News of the arrests came a day after thousands of pro-democracy protesters returned to Hong Kong streets, nine months after a demonstration that triggered 79 days of heated occupations in the semiautonomous Chinese city-state.A prominent leader of those protests, Joshua Wong, 18, said that there was a lack of evidence and that the arrests were a "farce" to smear localists, a group of hardline pro-Hong Kong, anti-mainland demonstrators.Read more: Who is Joshua Wong?"Even if you wanted to storm the Legislative Council, you wouldn't make explosives to get in, it's not reasonable," he told CNN.He also questioned why any suspects, who have yet to be named, would readily admit they were affiliated with a local radical group."No matter who did it, the government successfully vilifies the localists," he said, adding that he did not identify as a localist.Ronald Leung, a spokesman for a hardline localist group, repudiated the idea of making explosives. But he speculated that if police allegations were true, it could reflect the level of frustration developing for a minority in the pro-democracy camp."It's sad, because it shows that the rule of the central and local governments has failed, and people have only become angrier," he said. "It is only inevitable that people will find more and more radical ways of resistance."Political tension has ramped up in recent days as Hong Kong's government prepares to table a Beijing-backed reform package ahead of Hong Kong's 2017 elections.The proposal, if approved, would allow Hong Kongers to cast votes for their next leader -- if the candidates are first vetted by China.But pro-democracy legislators, who have just enough votes to veto the bill, have sworn to do just that.Wong told CNN on Monday that the chance of it passing was "zero."CNN's Ivan Watson, Vivian Kam and Agnes Chan contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615173854-hong-kong-explosives-found-4-large-169.jpeg</imagens>
        <videos>Sem vídeos disponíveis.</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/asia/hong-kong-arrests-explosives/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>North Korean soldier defects across border, South says</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/14</data>
        <hora>03:16</hora>
        <autor>By Jethro Mullen, K.J. Kwon and Jung-eun Kim, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>Seoul, South Korea (CNN)A North Korean soldier defected to South Korea on Monday across the heavily fortified border that separates the two countries, South Korean authorities said.The soldier crossed the Military Demarcation Line on foot from the eastern North Korean province of Gangwon, said a South Korean Defense Ministry official, who declined to be identified.Further details on the circumstances of the defection weren't immediately available. There was no reaction to the news on North Korean state media.The border between North and South Korea is considered to be the most heavily militarized in the world. The two countries technically remain at war, because the 1950-53 Korean War ended in an armed truce and not a peace treaty.North Korean soldiers have occasionally made it across the highly sensitive zone in the past.In 2012, one managed to cross the border unnoticed and knock on the door of a South Korean barracks, embarrassing the South Korean military and prompting a public apology from the defense minister at the time for the security lapse.But defections directly across the border from North to South Korea are rare.Most people attempt to flee the impoverished, oppressively ruled North by crossing the more open border into China and then trying to make their way to South Korea through other countries.More than 26,000 refugees from the North have reached the South since the end of the Korean War, according to the Unification Ministry in Seoul.The vast majority of them arrived during the past 15 years. But defection has become harder in recent years, the Unification Ministry says, and the number of people doing it has fallen significantly since Kim Jong Un succeeded his father as the North Korean leader.Separately, North Korea on Monday said it was willing to hold talks with the South -- but with conditions attached."If an atmosphere of trust and reconciliation is created between North and South Korea, there is no reason not to hold dialogue and negotiation between the two sides," a North Korean government statement carried by state media said.The conditions it set out included its often repeated call for South Korea to stop holding joint military exercises with the United States, a request that Seoul and Washington have consistently dismissed.Pyongyang also told Seoul on Monday that it plans to release two South Korean citizens this week, according to the South Korean Unification Ministry.North Korea said the two South Koreans -- a man in his late 50s with the surname Lee, and a woman in her early 50s with the surname Jin -- illegally entered North Korea on May 11. North Korea detained them the same month.The South Korean government said it believes the two went missing while traveling in China near the North Korean border. It expects to collect them Wednesday morning at Panmunjom, the "truce village" that straddles the border between the two Koreas.CNN's K.J. Kwon and journalist Jung-eun Kim reported from Seoul, and CNN's Jethro Mullen wrote from Hong Kong.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150419135235-03-kim-jong-un-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/04/korea-rare-look-inside-dmz.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/14/asia/north-korea-soldier-defection/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Chinese say 'I do' to creative -- and cheaper -- weddings</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>06:07</hora>
        <autor>By Steven Jiang, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>Beijing (CNN)Shiny rings, white gowns and luxury cars filled the mammoth national convention center, next to the Chinese capital's Olympic Bird's Nest stadium, one recent weekend.Armed with balloons, teddy bears and goody bags filled with coupons, throngs of salespeople stood outside their booths, shoving free gifts into the hands of visitors in an attempt to turn them into clients.Spread across two floors, more than 200 vendors competed at Beijing's Olympic-sized wedding expo for the attention -- and, more importantly, the wallets -- of thousands of young couples.PHOTOS: Tibetan couple's unconventional wedding pictures go viralEverything was on sale at a discount, but even a rough calculation on site pointed to the soaring cost of getting married in China.The total bill could easily exceed $20,000 -- an unimaginable sum just a few years ago -- counting a pair of rings, a bridal gown, a banquet, a photo shoot and a professional planner.In the United States, the average cost of a wedding -- excluding a honeymoon -- has a similar price tag of $25,200, according to the latest figure released by the Wedding Report, a market research firm.Although rapid economic growth has brought rising incomes, the average Chinese still makes only a fraction of their American counterpart.Government statistics show the annual disposable income for 2014 was only $3,283 per person in China.The ballooning cost of weddings has spurred a multi-billion-dollar industry, but also put a heavy burden on the more than 10 million couples marrying every year in the world's most populous nation, especially those who already feel financially strained trying to buy their first home and car.READ: How to get ahead on China's dating sceneFaced with a deep-rooted cultural preference for marriage, however, young Chinese preparing to tie the knot admit that cutting back is not always an option."It's a once-in-a-lifetime event -- so I have to show my commitment to her and her parents through the wedding," explained Wang Di, 23, who was looking for good deals at the expo even though he and his girlfriend don't plan to walk down the aisle for another two years."We may not care that much about the ceremony -- but the parents and other relatives do."Frustrated with family pressure, some rebellious Chinese couples have chosen to enter so-called "naked marriages" with no houses, no cars, no weddings -- and sometimes no rings.While the public seems to appreciate the philosophy of true love trumping everything else, most respondents in repeated surveys still reject the notion of disavowing all traditional trappings of marriage.Increasingly, though, less radical -- but more creative and affordable -- ideas are gaining popularity in big cities.At a courtyard house in suburban Beijing one recent Saturday, the dress code was casual, but everyone appeared to be having some serious fun at the bride and groom's "do-it-yourself" wedding. On stage, the bride had already kicked off her high-heels.The venue was the couple's home -- rented for only $2,500 a year from a local farmer. The decoration that emphasized fresh flowers and entertainment -- featuring a DJ and a band -- were both courtesy of their artistic friends.Adorning the brick walls were various home-made movie-style posters starring the bride and groom, including one showing them laughing in bed with the phrase "mad love" in bold yellow lettering splashed across the red duvet covering their bodies.READ: Glut of women at Shanghai's marriage market"Almost every wedding now goes through the same drill and I don't want that," said bride Zhang Yueyue, a marketing manager at an arts magazine."I think letting everyone have fun is the most important thing. Many Chinese weddings now are more about flaunting wealth and letting parents have 'face' through extravagance."Counting catering and tailor-made traditional Chinese dresses, Zhang and her artist husband spent less than $2,000 on their big day.With their modest incomes, the newlyweds agreed that saving from the wedding meant more money to start their married life together.Amid loud cheers and applause in the courtyard, some of the couple's guests already felt inspired."My budget won't be high either," said Zhao Mengsha, a colleague and friend of the bride who is planning her own summer wedding. "I just want a big party with some entertainment -- and most importantly lots of alcohol."That definitely sounds like a winning formula for a special occasion.READ: Chinese couples fly to London for wedding picturesREAD: China's leftover women choose to stay single</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615013730-china-wedding-cost-jiang-pkg-00001710-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/china-wedding-cost-jiang-pkg.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/asia/china-no-frills-weddings/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Australia urged to come clean over claims it paid traffickers</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>06:46</hora>
        <autor>By Euan McKirdy, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)The Australian government stands accused of shirking its international obligations to migrants following allegations it paid people smugglers to turn back a boat full of people seeking asylum.The country's immigration minister, Peter Dutton, said that his government would honor its international commitments."We will act within the law; we will act within our international obligations," he told reporters Sunday.However, migrant advocates have said that, should the allegations prove true, Australia is shirking its international obligations."Clearly helping people smugglers is not something that is supported by international conventions," Leonard Doyle, spokesperson for the International Organization for Migration (IOM), told CNN's John Vause."Indeed if they're traffickers by this point then that is something that would not be supported by anybody but we have to see what the facts are."The United Nations refugee agency's report cited firsthand accounts of people on board a ship that was diverted to Indonesia after coming in contact with Australian authorities.The boat -- carrying 65 migrants from Sri Lanka, Bangladesh and Myanmar -- was intercepted by the Indonesian navy after turning back from Australia on May 31, the UNHCR said.The migrants were transferred to an Indonesian customs vessel for four days before being sent on two boats to Indonesia, the UNHCR added, after speaking to some of the passengers.Australia has refused to confirm or deny the payment, and Prime Minister Tony Abbott went on the defensive Friday when asked about the claim. Abbott refused to "comment on operational matters," but said that the government would stop the boats "by hook or by crook."Along with Australian opposition politicians, Indonesia's foreign minister, Retno Marsudi, has demanded a response from the Abbott administration and said she had taken up the issue with Australia's ambassador to Jakarta.A ministry spokesman Armanatha Nasir told Australia's ABC News that Indonesia would investigate the UNHCR allegations."Of course on Australia's push-back policy we have been consistently saying they are on a slippery slope," ABC reported him as saying."Should this situation (be) confirmed ... it would be a new low."Speaking with reporters Sunday, Abbott again avoided giving a direct answer as to whether Australia had paid people smugglers to turn boats around."There's really only one thing to say here... and that is we have stopped the boats," CNN affiliate Sky News reported Abbott as saying."That's good for Australia, it's good for Indonesia and it's particularly good for all of those who want to see a better world because if the boats start again, the deaths start again. None of us should want to see deaths at sea and the only way to ensure that the boats stay stopped. It's important that the Indonesians know that the Australian government is absolutely resolute in our determination never to see this evil trade start up again."Relations between Indonesia and Australia remain strained following the execution of two Australian nationals, part of the so-called Bali 9 group of drug smugglers, in April. Australia recalled its ambassador from Jakarta following the incident.There are concerns that the plight of genuine refugees is being politicized by governments like Abbott's."At the end of the day migration is a complex issue. It's often reduced to political slogans and it's certainly not something to be managed through sloganeering. We can't just lock the door on people," IOM's Doyle told CNN."Around the world it's a phenomenon that needs collaboration and not simply closing the door on the problem."</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150428182048-tony-abbott---s046818710-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/australia-migrant-smugglers-vause-lklv.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/asia/australia-smuggling-payment-claims/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>How children are trafficked into Europe</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>18:13</hora>
        <autor>By Nima Elbagir, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
        <corpo>Sicily, Italy (CNN)The 13-year old boy looks off into the distance. He is slight of build with pale, almost yellowy eyes. When you see him you feel as if he has seen far too much already.He is carrying a burden far too heavy for his age -- but despite his ordeal so far, smuggled across continents from Africa to Europe, and now living in a care home, his future could be far worse depending which route he takes next.A CNN investigation spent months retracing the children's journey from Egypt to Italy. Speaking to social workers and authorities, children and parents, there is evidence that many of the children were smuggled into Italy by the same criminal networks, who once they are in country, use them for illegal activities.The Egyptian government agency charged with advising lawmakers on child protection matters told CNN that they believe in some cases the parents are guilty of trafficking, paying for their own vulnerable children to be smuggled so far from home in the hope of securing the family's future.We were interviewing this Egyptian boy and his friends in the picturesque piazza of a small Sicilian town.They came over to Italy together on an Egyptian smuggler ship. He was 12 at the time and crammed in with hundreds of others.He says his parents paid 35,000 Egyptian pounds (about $4,500) for the privilege, never guessing what it would really be like -- tossed around for nine days, surrounded by vomit, and scared, uncertain what would meet them on shore.I asked him what he would say to all the boys back at home, hoping to follow in his footsteps. He said he would warn them not to come but he also said he knew they wouldn't listen."Why would they? I didn't", he says. "Everyone does what their mind tells them. They won't take what we say."I asked if, having suffered so much, he'd make the journey again? "What can I do? Yes. The burden back home is still the same."Italian authorities say he is one of more than 1,000 young Egyptians sheltered in 100 Italian care homes now dotting the Sicilian countryside.The cobbled streets and 17th Century architecture is a very long way from the Nile Delta villages many of the boys have come from.I asked one of his friends if he calls his parents and what he tells them about their lives here, and if he's told them how close to death he came."I tell them nothing, just pleasantries and ask for their prayers. What difference would it make? They need me to make money."These boys tell us their parents went in to debt to raise the fare for their crossing. They saw it as an investment in what they hope will be a better future for the whole family. The children are expected to find work as soon as they can and start sending money home.Here at the care home, that's not possible so thousands of children are disappearing from the Italian social care networks.Italy's Ministry of Labor told us almost 4,000 Egyptian children disappeared from the care system.All the Italian authorities we spoke to who work with these children told us the pressure on the children would be unbearable even for an adult. They fear the consequences to their parents if the smugglers didn't get their money in full, or if the gamble doesn't pay off having sold what little of value they have.The missing children can't work legally. Social workers tell us that too often the children turn to drugs, even prostitution, to get by.Another boy we meet at the home asks me wistfully about Rome, which Italian authorities say is where so many of the disappeared head to.I told him Rome is dangerous for children on their own, especially on the streets. I told him the stories we'd heard from the Egyptian teenagers we'd met in Rome -- the exploitation and the homesickness.The Egyptian children in Rome tell stories of friends selling themselves on street corners -- but they sound suspiciously like they were speaking about themselves.I told him it's better to do it all the legal way and better for him to get an education.He listened politely until I'd finished then told me: "Better to be dead then useless."Dominique Van Heerden, Luca Muzi, Sara Sirgany and Mohamed Kazaz contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612105036-7-migrants-journey-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/elbagir-freedom-project-young-men-gone.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/europe/freedom-project-misery-trail-children/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Vatican to try ex-ambassador on child abuse charges</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>11:44</hora>
        <autor>By Eliott C. McLaughlin, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
        <corpo>(CNN)The Pope's former ambassador to the Dominican Republic, Jozef Wesolowski -- accused of offenses related to child abuse -- will be tried at the Vatican beginning next month, the Vatican said Monday.Wesolowski, 66, is the highest-ranking former Vatican official to be arrested for allegations related to the sexual abuse of minors and the first to be tried on such charges at the Vatican.Wesolowski is accused of possession of child pornography as well as offenses related to the sexual abuse of minors during his time as papal nuncio to the Dominican Republic.Before arriving in the Dominican Republic in 2008, Wesolowski was nuncio to Bolivia, Kazakhstan, Tajikistan, Kyrgyzstan and Uzbekistan. He began his career as a priest in Krakow, Poland, in 1972 and became a bishop in 2000.In August 2013, the Vatican said it was investigating Wesolowski and removing him from his post, but it did not give a reason. Monsignor Agripino Nunez Collado, a Catholic University rector, said an internal church report linked Wesolowski to child abuse and pedophilia."We have formally opened an investigation," Dominican Attorney General Francisco Dominguez Brito told reporters at the time. "Here we have to work with two legal aspects, first national laws and also international laws in his status as a diplomat, which implies other mechanisms of investigation and judgment."In January 2014, Vatican spokesman Federico Lombardi confirmed to the National Catholic Reporter that the Vatican's criminal court was investigating Wesolowski. Pope Francis had announced in July 2013 that he was extending the court's jurisdiction in sex abuse cases to include papal diplomats, making Wesolowski's case the first test of the ruling, the newspaper reported.The Holy See defrocked Wesolowski in June of 2014.Wesolowski is not only charged with offenses during his five years as nuncio of Dominican Republic, but also with child pornography charges committed in Rome between August 2013, when he was recalled, and September 2014, when he was arrested, a Vatican statement said. He also faces charges in the Dominican Republic and in his native Poland, Vatican Radio reported in August.Per the pornography allegations, Italy's Corriere della Sera reported in September that Wesolowski's laptop contained more than 100,000 files with pornographic images and videos, some showing naked teens, between the ages of 13 and 17, forced to have sexual relations with each other or with adults. Some had been downloaded from the Internet and others appeared to have been taken by the victims, the paper reported.Three minors and their mothers are among the prosecution's witnesses, according to Corriere della Sera. When Wesolowski was presented with a detention order in September, the paper reported, he issued a statement: "I can clear my position and explain the mistake."Though the Vatican provided few details on the sex abuse charges, Dominican investigative journalist Nuria Esperanza Piera Gainza reported in 2013 that her sources alleged Wesolowski was a regular in Santo Domingo's Colonial Zone, where he would drink alcohol and pay children to perform sexual acts in the Monument to Friar Antonio de Montesinos, on the outskirts of the zone."This will be a delicate and detailed procedure, requiring the most careful observations and insights from all parties involved in the trial," the Vatican said.Wesolowski's trial will involve information technology experts and international legal experts to evaluate evidence gathered in Santo Domingo, the capital of the Dominican Republic. The first hearing is scheduled for July 11.It's been reported that rather than being held in an Italian prison or Vatican detention cell, Wesolowski is under house arrest at a Vatican apartment for medical reasons.The church's sexual abuse guidelines allow local dioceses to make the initial decisions on the removal of accused priests. Papal nuncios, however, are appointed and supervised by the Vatican.Before he was elected pope, Francis said he supported a "zero tolerance" approach to clergy sexual abuse.In 2012, when Francis was still Cardinal Jorge Bergoglio, he said that when he was asked for advice by another bishop, "I told him to take away the priests' licenses, not to allow them to exercise the priesthood any more, and to begin a canonical trial in that diocese's court."Shortly after his election to the papacy, Francis told a senior Vatican official to "act decisively" against sexual abuse and carry out "due proceedings against the guilty."In July 2013, the pope made it a crime to abuse children sexually or physically on Vatican grounds. The acts were already crimes under church law, but are now specifically outlawed within the Vatican city-state, which is home to hundreds of people.CNN's Delia Gallagher and Diulka Perez contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615075110-jozef-wesolowski-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/former-vatican-official-faces-child-sex-abuse-trial.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/europe/pope-former-ambassador-dominican-republic-child-pornography-trial/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Saudi Arabia reports 5 cases of MERS</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/15</data>
        <hora>04:37</hora>
        <autor>By K.J. Kwon and Madison Park, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>Seoul, South Korea (CNN)In one sign of a possible return to normalcy, thousands of schools across South Korea re-opened on Monday after closures due to the deadly MERS outbreak.But it came with heightened awareness; children's temperatures were monitored in classrooms and teachers warned students to practice personal hygiene and frequently wash their hands.Not all schools have reopened; 440 remain shut as officials seek to stop the spread of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS).The World Health Organization had recommended re-opening institutions last week because transmission of the virus had not been linked to schools.Nearly four weeks into the South Korean outbreak, cases and deaths continued to mount on Monday.Five new cases of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome have been confirmed in South Korea, bringing the total to 150. Another person also died from the virus, raising the MERS death toll to 16, according to the country's Ministry of Health.The outbreak has sparked international concern, stalled the nation's economy and resulted in over 100,000 canceled tourist visits to the country. Korea's department store sales tumbled 16.5% compared with the same period last year and retail shops also decreased 3.4%, according to the Ministry of Strategy and Finance.The ongoing situation has put Korean authorities under scrutiny for their inability to contain MERS cases and President Park Geun-hye has seen her approval ratings plummet.In a news conference Monday, the Ministry of Health announced that a special task force had been sent to South Korea's second largest city, Busan, after learning that one of the most recently diagnosed MERS patient had visited several hospitals and clinics in the area."We are doing our best to stop the spread of MERS," said the Korean minister of health. "We are analyzing the CCTV with the help of Busan police," referring to tracking down who had been at the hospitals.On Sunday, a 61-year-old man died in a Busan hospital with MERS.South Korean health officials along with a WHO team said this weekend, that the outbreak was slowing, but additional cases were expected.READ: Should you be worried about MERS?Meanwhile, Saudi Arabia has recorded five cases of MERS in the past week, the official state-run Saudi press agency said Sunday, citing a weekly Ministry of Health statement. It included one death of a 73-year-old man who died in the city of Turaba and had a pre-existing condition.The strain of coronavirus that causes MERS was first identified in 2012 in Saudi Arabia, according to the WHO.The man believed to be "patient zero" in the current outbreak in South Korea visited Saudi Arabia in May, along with three other Middle Eastern countries. That 68-year-old patient went from facility-to-facility near or around Seoul before getting properly diagnosed. It triggered the hospital-based transmission of MERS in South Korea.The South Korean outbreak is the largest outside of Saudi Arabia -- over 5,000 people remain in quarantine.In Seoul, Samsung Medical Center -- one of the city's hospitals that has counted many of the nation's MERS cases among its patients and visitors -- announced Sunday that it will suspend all surgical procedures except for emergency surgery "to fully focus on responding to MERS."More than 50 confirmed MERS cases have been traced back to the medical center, according to the center's website.The medical center, located in Seoul's glitzy Gangnam district and considered one of the most prominent hospitals in the capital, issued an apology for its handling of MERS."We sincerely apologize with our heads bent to the people for causing great concern as Samsung Medical Center became the center (of) the spread of MERS," hospital President Song Jae-hoon said.CNN's K.J. Kwon reported from Seoul. CNN's Anas Hamdan reported from Atlanta. Journalists Jung-eun Kim and Han Sol, and CNN's Kay Guerrero and Khushbu Shah contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150607234201-south-korea-mers-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/s-korean-schools-reopen-mers-outbreak-novak-lklv.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/asia/south-korea-mers-outbreak/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Meet septuagenarian who beat virus</titulo>
        <data>2015/06/11</data>
        <hora>22:39</hora>
        <autor>By Kathy Novak, CNN</autor>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
        <corpo>Seoul, South Korea (CNN)She's 77 and has chronic asthma. But Kim Bok-soon has also survived MERS, the mysterious virus that's spreading in South Korea and putting thousands in quarantine.Ten people have now died from Middle East Respiratory Syndrome in South Korea; all elderly with pre-existing conditions.It can kill up to a third of people infected, but somehow Kim survived.She had an asthmatic episode and was treated at St. Mary's Hospital in Pyeongtaek between May 4 and May 16. South Korea's "Patient Zero," the man who brought MERS from the Middle East, was at the same hospital at the same time, as the virus started to spread.Kim was sent home with a week's worth of medication. When her condition didn't improve, she went back to St Mary's. Again, doctors sent her home but her symptoms got worse."I felt cold. I was sweating. I coughed all night. I wet my pants because I was coughing so hard," she said. "I thought, 'This is not good.' So I went back to St. Mary's hospital. But they were closed."The hospital had been shut down because dozens of people there had been infected with MERS: patients like Kim, medical staff and visitors. At least 37 cases of MERS have been linked to that initial outbreak.Kim checked into another nearby hospital. By then, South Korean authorities had been shocked into action. The doctors attending to her wore full biohazard suits."They came in covered from head to toe and took blood samples and other things," she said.The tests showed Kim had MERS and she was transferred to Seoul University Hospital.Still Kim, a devout Christian, said she wasn't scared. She continued to pray and rely on God's help as well as medical intervention.The medical staff continued to treat her, so swathed in protective gear that Kim couldn't see their faces properly.She guessed she had beaten MERS the day they came into her room without the white suits."They ran into my room, not even wearing doctors' gowns, and told me, 'You will be going back to general ward!'"I was so happy," she said. "All the doctors and nurses were there in the hallway. They all applauded."She was sent home the next day. "I felt like I could fly."</corpo>
        <imagens>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150611154436-mers-survivor-kim-bok-soon-large-169.jpg</imagens>
        <videos>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/11/south-korea-mers-patient-novak-pkg.cnn</videos>
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/11/asia/south-korea-mers-survivor/index.html</url>
    </noticia>
</noticias>